Amy Paslak

■ amy.paslak@gmail.com 🕠 apaslak

Summary

Stumbling into web design at a young age, I've been building apps, websites, and tools for over 15 years. I love solving problems and digging into code to determine how it works or could be improved. I absorb everything I can about my work and aspire to deliver elegant, scalable, and reliable code.

I love what I do, and aim to grow with like-minded engineers, building amazing tech.

Experience

Venmo — July 2019-present

MTS 2 Software Engineer

- Tech lead and mentor for Venmo's debit card. Used AWS CDK to build process by which users with expiring cards are reissued new ones.
- Led preparation of Venmo's platform monolith (Docker, Python 2.7/3.5) for development on Apple's M1 chips.
- Documented and proposed new process for provisioning features and products to users.
- Praised as a stellar documentarian, PR writer, gap closer, and teacher.

MTS 1 Software Engineer

- Led several cross-functional teams to rewrite existing ledger functionality using Cassandra and gRPC for a more scalable, feature-rich architecture.
- Tech lead for Venmo's credit card. Remained knowledgeable of all project pieces while specializing in repayments domain.
- Led final stages of testing the Venmo credit card, which included representing Venmo engineering in partner meetings and developing a bug triage process which allowed us to track, manage, and fix over 600 tickets in a few weeks.
- Pioneered Venmo's adoption of GitHub Actions for CI/CD, establishing workflows and actions that were reused across the organization.

Vibes Media — May 2012-July 2019

Senior Software Engineer / Team Lead

- Lead an agile team to maintain and improve an outdated CRM, built on Ruby/Rails with a Backbone.js and React front end.
- Championed large UI overhaul, which brought the look and feel of the CRM up to date with modern styling and allowed the team to clean up unused and duplicated styles.
- Successfully migrated CRM from company-owned servers into AWS.

Software Engineer II / Team Lead

- Lead a team of contractors to update the CRM from Rails 2.3 & Ruby 1.8.7 to Rails 3.2 & Ruby 2.1, with active development ongoing.
- Brief foray into contract work, where I built a small greeting card app and a lightweight conversation engine that integrated into the CRM.

Software Engineer I

- Introduced better code quality and standardization with code reviews and linting tools
- Mentored other engineers about common QA practices.

Skills

Languages and Frameworks

- Python Django, Pytest
- Ruby Rails, Rspec, Selenium, Jekyll
- Javascript jQuery, Node.js, Backbone.js, Jasmine

Data Systems

- Databases MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- Data Stores Redis

Miscellaneous

- Text Editors Vim
- Version Control Git
- Infrastructure Jenkins, GitHub Actions, Docker, Kubernetes

Education

Illinois Institute of Technology (IIT) -2008-2012

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

- Minor in Psychology
- Information Security specialization
- o Alpha Sigma Alpha sorority member